# DAN PATTERSON

Proven Full Stack Developer with 2+ years of experience creating accessible, responsive, and dynamic web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React. While in the military, I utilized Agile and Scrum methodologies for accountability and improvement of processes within the Explosive Ordnance Disposal (EOD) field. Always seeking personal development and growth, after the military, I enrolled and graduated from V School's Full Stack coding bootcamp, where I strengthened skills and expanded knowledge in creating and building web applications. As an accomplished Freelance Developer, I most recently created an application that provides users with accurate purchase/refinance quotes information using a noSQL database with MongoDB.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: HTML, JS, CSS
- Frameworks: Node.js, Express.JS, MERN
- Libraries: React, Mongoose
- Databases: MongoDB
- **Authorization**: Bcrypt
- CICD: GIT, Heroku, GitHub, Render
- Interpersonal Skills: Communication, Problem-solving, Teamwork

# In a developer role at your company I will...

- · Code within company coding standards and styles.
- Write fully automated code tests in adherence to best practices.
- Learn how to leverage the current CICD pipeline in place.
- Build responsive frontend designs to spec per the UX design.
- Build out API routes per RESTful design structure.
- Diligently prioritize multiple projects to ensure timely results.
- Be coachable and accepting of constructive criticism.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance - Full Stack Developer

Remote 2021 - Present

- Beam Lending Mortgage Calculator
  - Allows users to create a mortgage purchase or refinance quote for clients, perform calculations for a payoff amount, and track potential leads and current realtors. In building this web-based application, I displayed a working knowledge of React. JS, Node. JS, MongoDB, and RESTful methods to develop frontend design, client-side validations, proximity lookups, and the API framework.
  - Constructed API following RESTful standards, deploying the tool in a CICD pipeline through Render.
  - Dynamically renders a purchase/refinance quote with each update to the inputs.
  - Addressed authentication and security concerns with JWT tokens and the Bcrypt library.
  - Wrote all the financial calculation formulas so the quote pages are constantly updated with correct information.

### TradeView

- Allows users to search for their favorite stocks, view key market indicators, and save their favorites to a watchlist. In building this web-based application, I displayed a working knowledge of React.JS, Node.JS, MongoDB, and RESTful methods to develop frontend design, client-side validations, proximity lookups, and the API framework.
- Constructed API following RESTful standards, deploying the tool in a CICD pipeline through Render.
- Used React Router to seamlessly transition between tabs for this single page application.
- Utilized a financial API to get current stock information for potential investors.

#### V School - Teacher's Assistant

Remote 2022

Collaborated with a team of 3 Instructors to coach students on problem-solving techniques while advising on front-end and back-end web development applications, curriculum questions, computer setup, and web development related issues.

- Assisted over 70 students with curriculum related questions resulting in them learning and graduating from the program.
- Assisted students in deploying their projects to Heroku or Render which helped them complete the course work and improve their portfolio.
- Assisted students with computer or software problems preventing them from completing the course work.

# **Fidelity Investments - High Net Worth Associate**

American Fork, UT 2018 - 2019

As a High Net Worth Representative, I was responsible for enhancing the relationships with the clients who have assets of \$250,000 to \$1 million. These clients have complex service and investment needs, so the role required a lot of knowledge and expertise.

- Assisted over 12,000 clients with their inquiries and provided product and service level guidance.
- Processed customer requests to include options, equities, mutual funds, and fixed income trades and other specialized monetary requests.
- Gave presentations to over 100 community members on financial principles, which fostered a positive relationship and improved the company's image.

### US Army - Explosive Ordnance Disposal (EOD) Team Leader

**CONUS/OCONUS** 2008 - 2016

Led a 3-man team and was responsible for the identification, assessment, neutralization, and disposal of explosive devices and hazardous materials. Also had experience working closely with military units, law enforcement agencies, foreign militaries, and civilian authorities. My primary duty was to protect lives, property, and critical infrastructure from explosive threats.

- Planned and coordinated 6 months of pre-deployment training which resulted in 44 soldiers becoming proficient in EOD specific tasks and skills.
- Partnered with the Indian Army as the EOD expert in a joint training exercise. This collaboration required training, educating, and presenting information to the foreign military counterparts as well as their leadership. Overall, over 100 Indian soldiers were trained on EOD specific skills which helped strengthen the partnership between countries.
- Responsible for reporting accurate and detailed information of 50 EOD operations including incident reports, device analysis, and disposal methods employed. This information was crucial for intelligence purposes, future operations, and legal requirements.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### V School - Full-Stack JavaScript Web Development Certificate

Remote 2022

Full Stack Web Development course. Learned frontend programming using fundamental and advanced React concepts, JavaScript, HTML & CSS. Learned back-end/server-side programming using Express framework in Node.js, and database programming with MongoDB and Mongoose. Completed this course Remotely and a fast paced mastery-based method.

#### **Utah Valley University - Personal Financial Planning**

**Orem, UT** 2018

Learned and prepared for a career as a fee-for-service financial professional. We learned to address the specific needs of individuals, families, and businesses managing wealth and working to accomplish financial goals.